我叫沃尔特·哈特维尔·怀特
My name is Walter Hartwell White.
住在新墨西哥州阿尔布开克
I live at 308 Negra Arroyo lane
内格拉阿罗约巷308号  邮编87104
Albuquerque New Mexico 87104.
我要告诉所有的执法者
To all law enforcement entitles
这不是一段认罪声明
this is not an admission of guilt.
而是我跟家人之间的对话
I am speaking to my family now.
斯凯勒
Skyler...
你是我今生的至爱
You are the love of my life.
我希望你能了解这点
I hope you know that.
小沃尔特
Walter Junior...
在我心中你是个男子汉了
You're my big man.
在接下来的几天里
There are...
你们会
There are going to be some...
你们会知道
Things... things...
关于我的
That you'll come to
关于我的一些事情
Learn about me in the next few days.
我只想你们清楚一点
I just want you to know
无论发生什么事
That no... no matter how it may look
我心里牵挂的只有你们
I only had you in my heart.
永别了
Good-bye.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：缭乱    诺米    老奶奶    夜    joanna
时间轴：虫不知    傻蛐蛐     特效：Will
■
校对：小路    傻蛐蛐      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
绝
命
毒
师
第一季
第一集
三周前
沃尔特·H·怀特  结晶学质子辐射效应研究带头人
诺贝尔获奖研究项目杰出贡献奖
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
瞧瞧这个
Look at that.
这是素培根
That is veggie bacon.
甭管你信不信  零胆固醇的
Believe it or not. zero cholesterol.
吃起来也是一个味儿
You won't even taste the difference.
你觉得自己大概几点能到家
What time do you think you'll be home?
老时间
Same time.
我不希望他又缠你一整晚
I don't want him dicking you around tonight.
你的工资只给到5点
You get paid till 5
你工作到5点  这就行了
You work till 5 no later.
-生日快乐啊  -谢谢
- Hey, happy birthday.  - Well, thank you.
你又起晚了
You're late... again.
又没热水了
There was no hot water... again.
我有个简单应对的办法
I have an easy fix for that.
你早点起床
You wake up early
然后就可以第一个洗澡了
And then you get to be the first person in the shower.
我也有个办法
I have an idea.
为啥不买个新热水器呢
How about buy a new hot water heater?
这主意如何
How's that idea?
都提了成千上万次了
For the millionth and billionth time.
-止咳药喝过没  -喝了
- Did you take your echinacea?  - Yeah.
我觉得好多了
I think it's getting better.
这是什么鬼玩意儿啊
What the hell is this?
素培根  我觉得我们该注意下胆固醇了
It's veggie bacon. We're watching our cholesterol, I guess.
别给我  我要真培根
Not me. I want real bacon.
不要这假冒的破烂
Not this fake crap.
真是糟糕
Too bad.
吃了
Eat it.
这闻上去就像创口贴
This smells like band-aids.
给我吃了
Eat it.
成为老人家感觉怎么样
So how's it feel to be old?
当个小破孩感觉怎么样
How does it feel to be a smart ass?
对得好
Good.
赶紧吃吧
Eat your veggie bacon.
-准备好了吗  -好了  我能行
- You're all set? - Yeah, I'm fine.
-那好  回家见  -再见
- All right, see you at home. - Okay, see you.
化学
Chemistry
是研究什么的
It is the study of what?
谁知道
Anyone?
本恩
Ben.
化学品
Chemicals?
Chemicals.
不对
No.
化学
Chemistry is...
从学术层面说
Well technically
化学是一门研究物质的学科
Chemistry is the study of matter.
但是我更倾向于它是一门研究变化的学科
But I prefer to see it as the study of change.
现在  我们这样来设想一下
Now just... just think about this.
电子
Electrons.
它们
They...
改变自身的能级
Change their energy levels.
分子呢
Molecules.
分子改变自身的化学键
Molecules change their bonds.
这些元素
Elements.
进行组合从而形成化合物
They combine and change into compounds.
这就是所有生命的组成形式
Well that's... that's all of life.
对不对  我是说  这是个恒定的
Right? I mean it's just... it's the constant.
循环的过程
It's the cycle. It's solution
从生长到衰败  再到分解并溶化
Dissolution just over and over and over.
如此循环  周而复始
It is growth then decay then transformation.
这是如此的迷人  真的
It is fascinating really.
查德
Chad...
你课桌坏了吗
Is there something wrong with your table?
好了  离子键
Okay. Ionic bonds...
坐好了吗
Are you done?
离子键
Ionic bonds.
第六章节
Chapter 6.
一二三  这是是十块  再加十块一共二十
One, two, three makes 10, and 10 makes 20.
这是您的收据
Here's your receipt
然后拿着这张小票去找洗车员吧
And hand this claiming disc to your car wash professional.
-多谢  -欢迎再次光临
- Thank you.  - Come again.
他不来了
He's not coming.
他说他不干了
He said he quits.
现在由我来管收款机
I'm gonna run the register.
博格丹  别这样  我们说好的
Bogdan, no. We talked about this.
我人手不足  沃尔特
I'm shorthanded, Walter.
我能怎么办
What am I to do?
沃尔特
Walter?
我能怎么办
What am I to do?
怀特老师
Hey, Mr. White.
车轮擦亮点哦
Make those tires shine, huh?
你们肯定猜不到谁在给查德擦车
You will not believe who's cleaning Chad's car.
是怀特老师
Mr. White.
化学课老师
From chemistry.
惊喜
Surprise.
生日快乐  老爸
Happy birthday, Dad.
你回来得太晚了
You're so very late.
我说真的  斯凯勒
Really I'm serious, Skyler.
你的小腹平得就跟洗衣板似的
I mean you're flat as a washboard.
看上去太棒了
You look awesome.
她一点都看不出来  是吧
She's not showing at all, is she?
还是有那么一点的
She's showing a little.
卡门  这是我妹妹玛丽
Carmen this is my sister Marie.
-很高兴见到你  -你好
- Pleased to meet you.  - Hi.
格洛克-22  我的日常配枪
Glock 22. It's my daily carry, okay?
除非是B+式自动装填
I mean unless you're talking what plus b-plus loads
9毫米口径的都是扔货
you can forget the 9-mil all right?
我见过9毫米子弹从挡风玻璃上弹开
I seen one of those bounce off a windshield one time.
那枪是你射的吧
Yeah the way you shoot.
如果你要带把枪
If you're gonna bring a gun, babe.
就要带把够用的
You gotta bring enough gun.
点40口径的
40 caliber.
-这个太棒了  -很不错是吧
- This is awesome right here. - Nice, isn't it?
爸  你过来看看
Dad come check this out.
-我看到了  -过来拿着看
- Yeah I see it.  - Come on take it.
沃尔特  来看看
Check it out Walt.
不  不  只是有点重
No no it's just heavy.
所以警察才要男的当
That's why they hire men.
枪不咬人  知道吗
It's not gonna bite you, all right?
你看起来像拿着一杯热牛奶的基思·理查兹（滚石乐队）
Looks like Keith Richards with a glass of warm milk.
沃尔特
Hey Walt.
大家都听好了  听好了
Everybody listen up listen up listen up!
我要祝酒
I'm gonna give a toast.
为我的姐夫祝酒  来吧
A little toast to my brother-in-law. Come here.
沃尔特  你的大脑和威斯康星州一样大
Walt. You got a brain the size of Wisconsin.
不过我们并不是要说你坏话
But we're not gonna hold that against you.
因为你心地善良
Because your heart's in the right place man.
心地善良
Your heart's in the right place.
我们爱你
We love you man. We love you.
大家举杯  敬沃尔特
Everybody! To Walt!
干杯(墨西哥语)
Na zdorovje!
该死  打开第三频道
Oh shit. Turn on channel 3.
到目前为止我们逮捕了3个人
At which point we apprehended three individuals
并已将他们拘留
And placed them into custody.
我很自豪地说在打击
I'm proud to say the outstanding professionalism of
大量的冰毒贩卖案件中
My fellow agents at the Albuquerque district office
阿尔布开克分局的同仁们
Resulted in a substantial amount
表现了杰出的敬业精神
Of methamphetamine being taken off the streets.
有发生交火吗
Were any shots fired?
没有  我们的探员给嫌疑犯来了个出其不意
No ma'am. Our agents took the suspects by surprise.
电视还真他妈加油添醋
Damn the TV does add ten pounds.
加油添醋
Ten pounds?
你们两个  给我闭嘴坐下
Sit and spin. Both of you.
-汉克  -什么事
- Hank. - What?
不好意思  当作没看见这个
Sorry. You didn't see that.
太诱人了
So charming.
显然这是一个正在运行的组织
This is clearly an ongoing operation one
而且安排得当
Which was well organized...
汉克  一共多少钱
Hank, how much money is that?
大概有70万  很多吧
It's about 700 grand. That's a pretty good haul huh?
正如我说的  今天是阿尔布开克市民的好日子
As I say it's a good day for the citizens of Albuquerque
因为我们给予当地毒品交易沉重打击
When we can put this big a dent in the local drug trade.
不过有点不正常  那种现金
But that's unusual, isn't it? That kind of cash?
和我们之前破的大部分案子不同
Well it's not the most we ever took.
这钱来得很快
It's easy money...
被我们抓到就完了
Until we catch you.
沃尔特只要你开口  我就带你去跟踪
Walt just say the word and I'll take you on a ride-along.
你可以亲眼目睹我们如何捣毁冰毒实验室
You can watch us knock down a meth lab.
给你的生活增加点激情
Get a little excitement in your life.
是啊  有一天
Yeah, someday.
又是什么呀
Which one's this?
就是我在超级交换网上买的
Um, that faux-lalique vase
人造水晶花瓶
I picked up at the Super-Swap.
怎么样
How's it doing?
我已经预定了
Well, I met my reserve
还有两分钟开拍
and there's still two minutes.
什么事
What's up?
你说呢  小寿星
You tell me, birthday boy.
那你  周六有什么安排
Oh, hey, so, what's up for Saturday?
洗车
Mm. Car wash.
博格丹说需要我
Bogdan says he needs me.
几点结束  中午  一点钟
Till what time? Noon, 1 -ish?
大概两点吧  差不多
Probably 2, more like it.
那之后呢
And then what after that?
其实呢
Um, actually,
我打算开车去洛斯阿拉莫斯
I was thinking of driving up to Los Alamos.
那有一个...  游客中心举办展览
They've got this... The visitor center has an exhibit on
应该会很...
that's really supposed to be...
你不粉刷吗
You're not gonna paint?
刷  我会刷的
No, I'll paint.
只是这个...
It's just that this...
展出的是火星探测器的照片
You know, this exhibition on the Mars-rover photographs are...
我是说  细节一定相当清晰
I mean, the detail really is just supposed to be amazing.
我真的需要你能把漆刷完
It's just that I really need you to paint at some point.
-卧室早一天准备好...  -我知道
- The sooner that back bedroom gets finished... - I know.
我可以自己刷的
And I'd do it myself,
只是你说不愿意让我上梯子
except you said you don't want me standing on the stepladder.
-我会刷的  -好
- I will paint. -Okay.
这是怎么回事
What is going on down there?
没事...
No, it's...
他睡着了吗
Is he asleep?
不是...  没问题  他只是...
No, it's... No, it's nothing. He's just...
我说  你该小心点孩子  还有...
You know. Well, you gotta be careful about the baby and...
不用担心孩子
Well, don't worry about the baby.
这是专门为你的
This is just for you.
我们今天只弄你
We are just doing you tonight.
所以呢  你就闭上眼睛
So just close your eyes,
放松  顺其自然...
relax, and let it...
-闭上眼睛  -哦  好
- Close your eyes. - Oh, okay.
好了
Okay.
就这样
There you go.
对了
That's it.
就这样
There you go.
继续
Keep it going.
继...  太好了
Keep... Yes!
五十六耶
Fifty-six. Oh.
这真是太尴尬了
This is so embarrassing.
老实说  我没事
I am fine, honestly.
不过是轻微传染
It's just some bug going around.
先是我妻子  我儿子  现在我又染上了
First, my wife had it, then my son, and now me.
只是...  有一点胸痛
It's just... It's just like a chest cold.
可能还有点低血糖
Could be some low blood sugar as well.
我今天早饭吃得不是特别好
I didn't have the greatest breakfast this morning. Honestly, I didn't.
听我说  能帮个忙吗  可不可以
Hey, listen, can you do me a favor? Can you just, uh,
拐弯的时候让我下车
drop me off at a corner somewhere?
抱歉  不行
Uh, no, sorry.
我的保险真的不爽特别好
It's just that I don't have the greatest insurance.
请你深呼吸几下
Take a couple of deep breaths for me.
要我们帮你联系什么人吗
Is there anybody you want us to contact for you?
不  天哪  不用
Ha. No. God, no.
请你坐起来一下
Lean forward for me, would you?
怀特先生  你吸烟吗
Mr. White, are you a smoker?
不吸  从不
No, never.
为什么问这个
Why do you ask?
怀特先生
Mr. White.
Mr. white?
你说
Yes.
我刚说的你都明白了吗
You understood what I've just said to you?
肺癌  而且不能动手术
Lung cancer. Inoperable.
不好意思
I'm sorry...
我需要确保你真的明白了
I just need to make sure you fully understand.
最佳治疗方案是化疗
Best-case scenario with chemo.
这样我或许还能多活几年
I'll live maybe another couple years.
只是
It's just...
你的衣领上有芥末
You've got mustard on your...
就那儿  沾着芥末
Right there. Mustard there.
就那儿
Right there.
我的记录显示已经付过了
So my records show that I paid it
而且我确定我们最近没有欠款
and I certainly don't feel that we owe any late...
好  好吧
Yeah, all right. Um...
我会跟银行确认
Well I'll check with the bank
还有邮局
And maybe the post office
看看他们是否有弄丢
If they lost it or something.
好的  我再确认一下
Yeah, let me look into that.
好的
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
上个月你用万事达卡了吗
Did you use the mastercard last month?
在斯特普尔斯公司[办公用品连锁]花了15块88
15.88 at Staples?
要买些打印纸
We needed printer paper.
沃尔特  我们不用万事达卡的
Walt, the mastercard's the one we don't use.
好吧
Okay.
今天过怎么样
So how was your day?
不知道  我想
I don't know. It was um...
还不错
Fine.
沃尔特  我缺人手
Walt, come on. I'm shorthanded.
你帮忙去擦车  快点
I need you to do some wipe-downs. Come on.
-什么  -我叫你到外面去擦车
- What?  - I said I need you outside to do some wipe-downs.
你是来工作还是来发呆的
Are you here to work or to be staring at the skies?
快点走吧
Come on let's go.
快点伙计
Come on man.
博格丹  去你妈的
Fuck you Bogdan.
我说去你妈的
I said fuck you!
还有你那眉毛
And your eyebrows!
用这个擦吧
Wipe down this!
汉克
Uh Hank.
汉克  是我  沃尔特
Hank, it's Walt. Hey.
听着  没吵醒你吧
Oh listen... I didn't wake you did I?
好的
Oh good good.
不  不  没什么事  只是
No no nothing's wrong. I just uh...
我一直在考虑那个提议
I've been uh thinking about that offer...
跟你们一起行动
That ride-along.
右侧最后一幢房子  看到了吗
It's the last house on the right. See it?
不是二层的  旁边那幢
Not the two-story one, the one next to it.
有点儿那个  什么颜色来着
Kind of, uh, I don't know what do you call that? Um,
-绿色  -鼠尾草色
- green? - Sage.
"鼠尾草色"
"Sage?"
你他妈是陶器场出来的吗
Do you work at the fucking Pottery Barn? Jesus.
人家就叫鼠尾草色
Sage. That's the word for it.
你个傻缺就认得"绿"  这也怪我
My fault the only word your dumb ass knows is "green"?
我还认得"贱货"  这词怎么样
"Cheese-dick." I know that one. How about that?
总之  就是鼠尾草色那幢  看到了吧
Anyway, it's the, um, sage one. See it?
你们怎么知道那是个制毒窝点
So what tells you it's a meth lab?
据可靠线人报告
Star snitch says some dude
一个名叫"库克船长"的家伙在里面制毒呢
Goes by cap'n Cook lives up to his name in there.
还总往里面掺胡椒粉
Says he always adds a dash of chili powder.
这群精力旺盛的老墨
Ah you exuberant mexicans.
"库克船长"是个白人名字
Captain Cook that's a white boy's name.
"呆瓜"也是
Dopey as hell too.
是吗  这么着
Yeah? Tell you what.
我赌20块猜他是个老墨
I got 20 bucks that says he's a beaner.
-好的  -说定了
- All right.  - You're on.
快点  快点
All right come on come on.
好了  校车安全经过  开始行动
All right. School bus is clear. Got the green light.
收到
Copy that.
看我们怎么收拾他们
Watch this.  Makes them shit.
上上上
Go go go.
制毒窝点在天气好时尤其危险
Meth labs are nasty on a good day.
一旦混合错误就会产生芥子气
You mix that wrong you got mustard gas.
应该是磷化氢
Phosphine gas.
我觉得是
I think.
当然没错
Yeah exactly.
吸一口就会丧命  所以要戴面罩
One whiff will kill you. That's why the respirators.
房子搜查完毕  拘捕一名嫌犯
House is clear. One suspect in custody.
收到
Copy that.
嫌犯会是拉美裔的吗
The suspect might he be of the latino persuasion?
驾照上的名字是埃米利奥·小山
Driver's license says Emilio Koyama.
亚裔的
Asian!
给钱吧  蠢货
Pay up sucker.
名字是埃米利奥
First name Emilio.
说明至少有一半墨西哥血统
That's at least half a beaner.
这么着吧  算你10块好了
Tell you what, I'll let you off for a 10.
打起精神吧  傻瓜  你们不是还有詹妮弗·洛佩兹嘛
Cheer up gomey. You people still got J.lo.
汉克  我能进去看看吗
Hank, do you think I might get to go inside?
看看制毒窝点
See the actual lab?
可以  跟你说吧
Yeah. Yeah I tell you what
我们要先进去
We're gonna go peek our heads in
仔细检查下
Check it out first.
你稍等一下
Stay here a minute.
天哪
Oh my god.
平克曼
Pinkman?
船长
是我
It's me.
就我一个
I'm alone.
你是怎么找到我的
How'd you find me?
你还在我们的资料库里面
You're still in our filing system.
这地方是你阿姨的吗
So your aunt owns this place right?
是我的
I own it.
没人在找你
No one's looking for you.
你来这干什么
Why are you here?
我很好奇
I was curious.
事实上我没期待你有什么作为
Honestly I never expected you to amount too much
但是甲基安非他明
but methamphetamine?
我万万没有想到
I didn't picture that.
这个能赚很多钱吧
There's a lot of money in it huh?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
-真的  -一点不明白
- No?  - Not a clue.
库克船长
Captain Cook?
不是你吗
That's not you?
我说了  没人在找你
Like I said no one is looking for you.
听着  我不知道你来这儿干嘛
Look I don't know what you think doing here.
怀特老师
Mr. White
如果你想拿上帝那套狗屎说辞
I mean if you're planning on giving me some bowl winder
劝我去自首的话
About getting right with jesus by turning myself in...
-我不会的  -高中已经是很久远的事情了
- Not really.  - High school was a long time ago.
你又不是什么灵魂工程师  赶紧滚吧
You ain't welcome back kotter,so step off.
少说废话
No speeches.
就说几句
Short speech.
你今天被抓的的那个同伙叫什么
You lost your partner today. What's his name?
埃米利奥
Emilio?
埃米利奥就要去蹲大狱了
Emilio is going to prison.
毒品缉查局抄了你的窝还有钱
The DEA took all your money your lab.
你一无所有了
You got nothing.
话说回来
Square 1.
你懂得怎么贩毒
But you know the business.
而我掌握着化学技术
And I know the chemistry.
我在想
I'm thinking...
或许我们可以合作
Maybe you and I could partner up.
你想制造冰毒吗
You want to cook crystal meth?
就凭你
You?
你和我
You and uh... and me?
没错
That's right.
要么答应我
Either that...
要么我告发你
Or I turn you in.
这是什么鬼东西
What the hell is this?
我怎么知道
Damned if I know.
我在描述里写的是马赛克手工艺品
I described it as mosaic folk art.
这东西居然有人买
And somebody bought it?
是啊  明尼阿波利斯有个人
Yeah, some guy in Minneapolis.
14美元  不算邮费
Fourteen dollars plus shipping.
真棒
Yes.
照这样下去  再过五六十年你就发了
At this rate, in 50 or 60 years you'll be rich.
小说写得怎么样
So how goes the novel?
不是小说  其实我...
It's not a novel, actually, which l...
你没在写小说
You're not writing a novel?
你跟我说你在写小说
You told me you were.
不  是短篇故事
No. Short stories.
我说的是  如果好故事足够多
I said that if eventually I have enough good ones, that maybe I'll try
我或许会试着出版短篇小说集
and publish another collection.
小说集不好卖的
Those really didn't sell.
我只是觉得小说会好卖一些
I just thought a novel would be easier to sell.
对  可能吧
Yeah, well, maybe so.
如果你需要我读  我可以提些批评意见
Ever want me to read anything, I could critique it for you.
哦  不用
Oh. No.
我是说  我现在还没到...
I mean, I'm just not at that stage where I...
不用了
No.
提议随时有效
Open offer.
沃尔特最近怎么样
So, what's up with Walt lately?
你指什么  他挺好
What do you mean? He's fine.
他看起来有点
He just seems,
我也说不清  他比平时话少
I don't know. Quieter than usual.
人到半百是件大事
Well, turning 50 is a big deal.
比如说  我对40岁可一点都不期待
I mean, I'm sure as hell not looking forward to 40.
眼看自己就要不中用了
You're gonna be a complete basket-case.
这么说他遇到中年危机了
So it's a mid-life crisis.
没有  他只是不爱说话
No. He's just quiet.
性生活怎么样
How's the sex?
玛丽  我的老天
Marie, Jesus.
看来有答案了
I guess that answers that.
你就坐着不动
You just gonna sit there?
这个  看看这个
This. Look at this.
凯氏烧瓶
Kjeldahl-style recovery flask
800毫升容量  非常少见
800 milliliters, very rare.
我还带来了常用的试验装置
You got your usual paraphernalia
格里芬烧杯  锥形烧瓶
Griffin beakers your erlenmeyer flask.
但还有更牛掰的东西
But the PA resisted staff.
圆底烧瓶  5000毫升的
A round bottom boiling flask. 5,000 milliliters.
我都是用那种的
Well, I cook in one of those.
大个儿的
The big one.
这种样子的吗
One of these?
不行  这是个量瓶
No,this is a volumetric flask.
你不可能用这种玩意制毒的
You wouldn't cook in on of these.
我确实是
Yeah I do.
不  你不可能的
No, you don't.
量瓶只能用于普通混合或者滴定
A volumetric flask is for general mixing and titration.
不可以用来加热
You wouldn't apply heat to a volumetric flask.
烧瓶才可以加热
That's what a boiling flask is for.
我的化学课你一点都没学到吗
Did you learn nothing from my chemistry class?
是的  你挂我科了
No. You flunked me.
-记得吗  -难怪呢
- Remember? - No wonder.
蠢货
Prick.
告诉你吧  这可不是化学课
Now let me tell you something else. This ain't chemistry
这是艺术
This is art.
制毒是艺术
Cooking is art.
我制的毒很赞  少对我说教
And the shit I cook is the bomb so don't be telling me.
你制的那是垃圾
The shit you cook is shit.
我见过你的装备  太荒谬了
I saw your setup. Ridiculous.
我和你不是去制造垃圾
You and I will not make garbage.
我们要制出稳定的化学纯产品
We will produce a chemically pure
就像广告宣传的一般
And stable product that performs as advertised.
不掺假  不掺奶粉  也不掺胡椒粉
No adulterants. No baby formula. No chili powder.
不  不  胡椒粉是我的标识
No no chili p is my signature.
不再是了
Not anymore.
好  那咱们走着瞧吧
Yeah well we'll see about that.
-这他妈什么玩意儿  -实验室防护用具
- What the hell is this?  - Lab safety equipment.
我们还会装个紧急洗眼台
We're also gonna have an emergency eye wash station.
这些化学药品及其蒸气都有毒
These chemicals and their fumes are toxic.
你不知道我现在告诉你
In case you didn't know that.
只要你乐意  你穿得像个同性恋都行
Well you can dress up like a faggot if you want.
我可不穿
Not me.
听好  这些东西最多只能在这放一天
Listen this stuff doesn't stay more than a day.
什么  我还以为我们要在这里制毒
What? I thought we were gonna cook here.
不  我们不在这里弄
No we're not gonna cook here.
这是我家  我可不在自己的地盘上犯事
Okay this is my house. I don't shit where I eat.
好  那我们到哪里干活
Well, then where are we gonna work?
你说呀
You tell me.
这是你的买卖  冒烟也得在你家冒
This is your deal, man. You wanna smoke it up, smoke it up at your house.
不  我看不行
No, I didn't think so.
那么
Well...
不然我们租间那种个人储藏室
What if we rented one of those self-storage places
就是那些橙色小车库  在那里制造
You know those little orange garages worked out of there?
不行
No.
他们都盯着呢  派了警犬在附近查探
They're on to that. They got dogs that sniff around.
旅行车  正合你意
RV. That's what you want.
像温尼巴古车那样的吗
What like a Winnebago?
对
Yeah.
我知道有个家伙正要转手
I know a dude who wants to sell his.
他平时开去野营
He just goes camping with it.
一个移动冰毒制造室
But a mobile meth lab?
超赞  我是说
That'd be the bomb. I mean
咱们开到郊外去
Drive way out in the boonies.
避过所有耳目
Be all evasive.
伙计  这还不到7000块  那人要价8500
Dude this isn't even 7 grand. My guy wants 85.
这是我全部的积蓄了
This is all the money I have in the world.
你是毒贩  去还价
You're a drug dealer. Negotiate.
你不是我读书时的那个老师了
You are not how I remember you from class
一点都不像了
I mean like not at all.
-我得走了  -等等  等一下
- I gotta go.  - Wait wait. Hold on.
告诉我你为什么要做这行
Tell me why you're doing this.
说正经的
Seriously.
你又为什么干这行
Why do you do it?
主要为钱
Money mainly.
-我也是为这个  -别开玩笑了
- There you go.  - Nah come on!
像你这么正直理智的人
Man some straight like you giant stick up his ass
突然临老撞邪了
All of a sudden at age what 60
这是要去搞破坏吗
He's just gonna break bad?
-我50岁  -这真太离谱了
- I'm 50.  - It's weird, is all okay?
完全看不出来  听着
It doesn't compute. Listen...
如果你这是发神经还是什么
If you've gone crazy or something...
你要是  你要是发神经
I mean if you've... If you've gone crazy
或者抑郁  我只是说说
Or depressed I'm just saying...
这些问题  我得了解
That's something I need to know about.
好吗  我是说这对我有影响
Okay? I mean that affects me.
我觉悟了
I am awake.
什么
What?
买下旅行车
Buy the RV.
我们明天开工
We start tomorrow.
试得怎么样
How's it coming in there?
还好
Fine.
要我还是你爸进去帮忙吗
Do you want me or your dad?
爸
Dad.
裤腰大小怎样  会不会太紧
So how are those feeling in the waist? Are they too tight?
要是太紧你就别穿了
'cause you don't want to get them if they're too tight.
这是防缩水的料子
They're pre-shrunk.
不想试试别的款型吗
Are you sure you don't want to get a different kind.
像是  修身牛仔裤
Like you know the skinny jeans?
现在正流行呢
Those are really supposed to be in style now.
玩轮滑的人常穿
The skaters wear them.
我看起来像玩轮滑的吗
Do I look like a skater?
那好吧
All right.
妈妈  瞧瞧我的裤子
Mom look at my big-boy pants.
妈妈  帮我拉拉链
Mommy could you zip up my big-boy pants?
-别去  -什么
- Don't.  - What?
别管
Don't.
沃尔特
Walt.
-他去哪  -我也不知道
- Where...  - I have no idea.
知道吗  睬到别睬他们
You know what? Don't even look at them.
他们的行为很蠢
They're obviously very stupid.
我觉得
I think that um...
我觉得这裤子你穿着很好看
I think those jeans look really good on you.
你要喜欢就买下来  好吗
You should get them if you like them okay?
你在这儿待一会儿好吗
Why don't you just hang out here for a second?
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
好
Fine.
妈妈  我想
Mommy I think I pinched a loaf
我拉在新裤子里了
In my brand-new big-boy pants.
-你在搞什么  -怎么了先生
- What are you doing?  - What's wrong chief?
走路不太灵便吗
Having a little trouble walking?
放开我  放开我
Get off me. Get off me!
我不会让你好过的
I'll mess you up man.
你只有一次机会  你最好把握好
Well you'll have one shot. You better make it good.
等着你的女朋友们来帮忙吗
What are you waiting for your girlfriends?
快动手啊  打啊
You better go. Take it.
抡起你的拳头  打啊
Take your shot. Take it!
来啊  别扭扭捏捏的
Come on. Come on.
走吧  我们走吧  咱们走
Come on let's get outta here. Let's go.
神经病
Psycho.
除了奶牛什么都没有
Yeah nothing but cows!
那边大概2英里处有些大牛棚
Got some big cow house way out that way like 2 miles
但是没看见人
But I don't see nobody.
牛棚吗
Cow house?
是啊  它们住那儿
Yeah where they live.
奶牛
The cows.
不管这些了
Whatever man.
就在这开工吧
Yeah let's cook here.
牛棚
Cow house.
上帝保佑
God help me.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
这些是我的光鲜衣服
These are my good clothes.
我可不能带着一身毒品味回家
I can't go home smelling like a meth lab.
可以啊  我就是这样的
Yeah you can. I do.
那条
Those?
你至少会穿着那条吧
Those uh... you're keeping those on, right?
开工吧
Come on.
别浪费时间了
Daylight's burning.
老天
Oh my God.
这样  这样很适合你
Oh this is uh... this is a good look for you.
你大概就是世上第二强同志了
And you're maybe only the world's second biggest homo.
闭嘴  过来帮忙
Would you shut up and help me?
就这样
Oh yeah.
就是这样
Oh yeah work it.
宝贝  就是这样
Baby work it.
把那关掉
Turn that off!
这是晶体级冰毒
This is glass grade.
我说  你真的
I mean you got...
老天你真的做出了两三英寸长的结晶体
Jesus you got crystals in here 2 inches 3 inches long.
这可是特纯级别的
This is pure glass.
你他妈的真是艺术家
You're a damn artist.
这是艺术  怀特老师
This is art, Mr. White.
事实上  这只是基础化学
Actually it's just basic Chemistry
不过谢谢你  杰西  我很高兴这合格了
But thank you Jesse. I'm glad it's acceptable.
合格  你他妈整个一"食神"嘛
Acceptable? You're the goddamn Iron Chef.
全天下吸毒的人
Every jibbhead from here to
都会想尝尝这个的
Timbuktu is wanna taste it.
现在我先来  享受一下
Now I gotta... I gotta try this.
不  不行
No. No.
我们只贩毒  不吸毒
We only sell it. We don't use it.
谁说的
Okay since when?
你《迈阿密风云》看多了吧
Listen you've been watching way too much Miami Vice.
不吸是不可能的
That ain't happening.
那  现在怎么办
So... What now?
下一步怎么做
How do we proceed?
明天再多做点
We cook more tomorrow.
同时
Meantime...
我知道找谁去谈
I know just the guy to talk to.
小疯  最近如何
Kraze how you doing my man?
又弄了条狗  不赖啊  伙计
You got a new dog. Right on man.
叫什么名字
What's his name?
我以前也有条这样的狗  有它两个大
Yeah, I had a dog like that once, except maybe like twice as big.
超纯种的
Super-purebred.
要是我的话  我会训练它
Now me personally I would train him
怎样找到毒品
To go straight for the, uh, nut ----
闭嘴  一手交钱一手交货
Just shut your mouth and show me your money.
我不是来买货的  伙计
I ain't buying ese.
而是来卖货的
I'm selling.
告诉我这是不是你见过的
Tell me that ain't the finest Scante
最优的冰毒
You ever laid eyes on.
去试试看
Go ahead try it.
小乖乖
Hey Poochie.
最近怎样
How you doing?
我的老天
Jesus Christ.
怎么样  我说吧
See? What'd I say?
还好
It's all right.
还好  还好
It's all right? It's all right?
是还好
Yeah. It's all right.
怎么  重操旧业了
So what? You back in business?
是啊  我回来了
Hell yeah I'm back.
来势汹汹
With a Vengeance.
窝囊废也得讨生活啊
Vato loco gotta make a living.
你知道你表弟被抓的事了吧
You know with your cousin gone away and all.
听着  伙计  埃米利奥那事
And listen homes about that.
我真的很伤心
It really broke me up about Emilio.
那哥们就像我兄弟
That dude is like my brother.
他还好吧  去看过他了吗
He okay? You talk to him?
恩  我和他聊过了
Yeah, yeah I talked to him.
他说条子来的时候
He said when the feds came
你还在跟隔壁的马子鬼混
You were out sticking it in some neighbor lady.
你知道的  我正好逃过了一劫
Hey you know, I got lucky twice.
我不知道  伙计
I don't know, man.
埃米利奥觉得
Emilio...
你临阵脱逃了
He thinks maybe you dimed on him.
他胡说
That is bullshit.
疯狂小八  他在说胡话
That is bullshit, krazy-8!
他敢这么想我他妈踢死他
I should kick his punk ass for even thinking that.
那啥  下次再去看埃米利奥的时候
You know what? Next time you talk to Emilio
你帮我转告他  好吗
You tell him for me, all right?
何不你自己跟他说
Why don't you tell him yourself?
-他今天早上保释出来了  -来呀  笨蛋
- Made bail this morning.  - Go ahead Pendejo.
踢死我呀
Kick my ass.
听我解释...
Hey listen...
这是哪搞来的
Where did you get this?
凭你这小杂种是做不出来的
I know your little punk ass didn't cook it.
伙计
Hey man.
你这算啥  裸体主义者
You some kind of nudist?
你就是在这里造出那高级货来的
That's some stone-fine tick tick you been cooking there ese.
来跟着我干怎么样
How about you come work for me?
出价合理的话
I'd be willing to sell it to you if...
我愿意给你供货
The price is right.
这都你一个人造出来的吗
You out here all by yourself huh?
我认识你
I know you.
我被抓的时候他就在那  跟缉毒组在一块儿
He was there when I got busted. He's with the DEA!
没有
No.
你他妈该死的告密者
You rata-snitch motherfucker!
快跑  怀特老师  快跑
Run Mr. White! Run!
把他们俩都给毙了
I say we cap them both.
那批货真的是你制的
You really cook up that batch?
是
Yeah.
你是个艺术家
You an artist.
真是太可惜了
It's a damn shame.
等等  等一下
Wait! Wait a minute.
听我说
Listen to me.
我把秘方给你们
I'll teach you my recipe.
你刚怎么说来着  也想造出这样的货
What do you say? You want to cook like me?
放了我们俩
You let us both live...
我就教你们
And I will teach you.
这里不许抽烟
Put the cigarette out.
拜托了
Please.
红磷
快点  伙计
Move it homes.
没那么多时间跟你耗
We ain't got all day.
好的
Okay.
怎么了
What happened?
你怎么他们了
What'd you do to them?
潮湿状态下的红磷
Red Phosphorus in the presence of moisture
遇热会加速产生磷化氢
And accelerated by heat yields Phosphorus Hydride.
一种剧毒气体
Phosphine gas.
吸入这么小小一口
One good whiff and...
我们得
We gotta...
我们得  清理下现场
We gotta... clean this up.
你去哪了
Where were you?
我不知道你最近怎么了  但是
I don't know what's been going on with you lately but...
没事  我很好
Nothing. I'm fine.
不管是怎么回事
Whatever it is...
我告诉你
I'll tell you this.
我不喜欢你有事瞒着我
I do not like it when you don't talk to me.
最不济也就是把我甩了罢了
The worst thing you can do is shut me out.
沃尔特  那还是你吗
Walter is that you?